<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-12T20:24:54-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ben Ward - Audio DSP Developer</title><subtitle>A Website to highlight my work in audio developement, particularly my plugins</subtitle><author><name>Ben Ward</name><email>brw775586@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Spectral Processing and the Phase Vocoder</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/PhaseVocoder/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spectral Processing and the Phase Vocoder" /><published>2026-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2026-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/PhaseVocoder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/PhaseVocoder/"><![CDATA[<p>This post is an overview of my experience creating a spectral processing plugin, the challenges involved, and a general overview of some of the processes I learned about, with specific reference to th Phase Vocoder.</p>

<p>During my Master’s program, one of my required courses, Musical Signal Processing, served as my introduction to advaced DSP concepts like filter design and the fourier transform. I found this class fascinating, as I knew there was a depth of theory underlying tools such as pitch shifters, and harmonizers, but had never had the concepts fully expressed to me, and knew this class was providing the information I was looking for. Because of this, it quickly became one of my favorite classes. I used the final project for this class as an opportunity to apply some of the concepts I learned in this class, and the result is on-going plugin project aptly titled the “Spectral Processor”.</p>

<p>When I first began conceptualizing this project, my main motivation was to apply the FFT process for some type of spectral processing. The most accessible and straightforward process I could think of was pitch shifting, so I decide to set that as my primary goal.</p>

<p>###</p>]]></content><author><name>Ben Ward</name><email>brw775586@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="DSP" /><category term="plugins" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an overview of my experience creating a spectral processing plugin, the challenges involved, and a general overview of some of the processes I learned about, with specific reference to th Phase Vocoder.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reviving Magenta’s Tensorflow Library</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reviving Magenta’s Tensorflow Library" /><published>2025-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hello%202</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-2/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I’ve completed my thesis outlining my work updating an outdated tensorflow library used for many early neural audio synthesis projects.</p>

<p>This project served as my final thesis for my Master’s degree at Maynooth University. My initial goal for the project was to implementing some of these earlier projects into a distilled plugin to highlight the limits of neural audio in real-time plugins. My target repository for this modification was Google’s Magenta project, a large repository with many intersting neural audio applications. However, the Magenta repository was based on Tensorflow 1, which has since been deprecated, leaving future audio tinkerers bereft. Thus, my goal for this project evolved to reviving the Magenta framework to make use of the modern Tensorflow 2 paradigm. A full report of the project, as well as the final results, will soon be available under my projects page.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ben Ward</name><email>brw775586@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="intro" /><category term="welcome" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I’ve completed my thesis outlining my work updating an outdated tensorflow library used for many early neural audio synthesis projects.]]></summary></entry></feed>